Finding Aid for the Nan Britton Papers LSC.0467
UCLA Library Special Collections
Nan Britton papers
1902-1966
UCLA Library Special Collections
Britton, Nan
LSC.0467
6.5 Linear Feet (13 boxes and 1 oversize box)
Restrictions on Access
Open for research. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
UCLA Catalog Record ID
UCLA Catalog Record ID: 9942304173606533
Scope and Content
Collection consists of correspondence, manuscripts, clippings, photographs, and memorabilia.
Manuscripts for publication; Women authors, American -- Archives.; Britton, Nan,1896- --Archives.; Harding, Warren G. (Warren Gamaliel)
- Books
  - Murphy, James W. Last Speeches of President Warren G. Harding, 1923. (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Johnson, Willis Fletcher. The Life of Warren G. Harding, 1923. (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Asher, Carl. He Was Just Folks, 1923. (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - In Memoriam - Warren G. Harding, 1924. (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Blythe, Samuel G. A Calm Review of a Calm Man, 1923. (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Means, Gaston. The Strange Death of President Harding, 1930. (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Jenks, Anton Shrewsbury. A Dead President Makes Answer to The President's Daughter, 1928. (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - DeBarthe, Joseph. The Answer, 1928. (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - Sytton, Dan. The Vice President's Son, 1928. (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - Smith, Ina R.T. Dear Mr. President, 1949. (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - Our Common Country, speeches of Warren G. Harding, 1921. (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - The Mirrors of Washington, 1921. (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Allen, Frederic Lewis. Only Yesterday, 1931. (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Britton, Nan. The President's Daughter, 1930. (Box 17, Folder 4)
    General note
    With First Edition attached to flyleaf.
  - Britton, Nan. Honesty or Politics, 1932. (Box 17, Folder 5)
    With photocopy of dustjacket.
  - Britton, Nan. Mes Amours Avec Le President Harding, 1931. (Box 17, Folder 6)
- Correspondence
  - Charles E. Kelley (Nan Britton's New York attorney), 1928. (Box 8, Folder 15-16)
    Folders 1 and 2 of 5.
  - Charles E. Kelley (Nan Britton's New York attorney), 1930-1931. (Box 8, Folder 18)
    Folder 4 of 5.
  - Charles E. Kelley (Nan Britton's New York attorney), 1928-1930. (Box 8, Folder 17)
    Folder 3 of 5.
  - Charles E. Kelley (Nan Britton's New York attorney), 1932-1936. (Box 8, Folder 19)
    Folder 5 of 5.
  - Nathan Loeser (one of Nan Britton's attorneys in Cleveland), 1928. (Box 9, Folder 1)
    Folder 1 of 5.
  - Nathan Loeser (one of Nan Britton's attorneys in Cleveland), 1928-1929. (Box 9, Folder 2)
    Folder 2 of 5.
  - Nathan Loeser (one of Nan Britton's attorneys in Cleveland), 1929-1930. (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Nathan Loeser (one of Nan Britton's attorneys in Cleveland), 1930. (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Nathan Loeser (one of Nan Britton's attorneys in Cleveland), 1930-1931. (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - William F. Marsteller and Seavey Moor, 1927. (Box 9, Folder 6)
    Folder 1 of 9. Labelled The situation in Cleveland.
  - William F. Marsteller and Seavey Moor, 1931. (Box 9, Folder 7)
    Folder 2 of 9. Samples of letters and orders received concerning the DeBarthe book, and replies thereto.
  - William F. Marsteller and Seavey Moor, 1928-1930. (Box 9, Folder 8)
    Folder 3 of 9. re Mr. Fryefield.
  - William F. Marsteller and Seavey Moor, 1929-1930. (Box 9, Folder 9)
    Folder 4 of 9.
  - William F. Marsteller and Seavey Moor, 1931. (Box 9, Folder 10)
    Folder 5 of 9.
  - William F. Marsteller and Seavey Moor, 1931. (Box 9, Folder 11-12, Box 10)
    Folders 6 through 8 of 9.
  - William F. Marsteller and Seavey Moor, 1932. (Box 10, Folder 2)
    Folder 9 of 9.
  - William F. Marsteller and Mrs. Britton (Nan's mother) re McDowell sisters, 1928-1931. (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Frank Vincent and George Landy, 1930. (Box 10, Folder 4)
    re proposed film of The President's Daughter.
  - Elizabeth Ann Guild, Incorporated - miscellaneous, 1927-1933. (Box 10, Folder 5)
    Folder 1 of 2.
  - Elizabeth Ann Guild, Incorporated - miscellaneous, 1927-1933. (Box 10, Folder 6)
    Folder 2 of 2. Includes financial reports for 1927.
  - Elizabeth Ann Guild, Incorporated - sheets from minute book and other papers, 1927-1928. (Box 10, Folder 7)
    Folder 1 of 4.
  - Elizabeth Ann Guild, Incorporated - sheets from minute book and other papers, 1928-1932. (Box 10, Folder 8)
    Folder 2 of 4.
  - Elizabeth Ann Guild, Incorporated - sheets from minute book and other papers, 1927-1932. (Box 10, Folder 9)
    Folder 3 of 4.
  - Elizabeth Ann Guild, Incorporated - sheets from minute book and other papers, 1929-1931. (Box 10, Folder 10)
    Folder 4 of 4. Includes material re the Golden Rule Foundation.
  - Elizabeth Ann Guild, Incorporated - general - Toussaint Dubois, 1927-1928. (Box 10, Folder 11)
    Folder 1 of 7.
  - Elizabeth Ann Guild, Incorporated - general - Gordon Lathrop, 1927-1928. (Box 10, Folder 12)
    Folder 2 of 7.
  - Elizabeth Ann Guild, Incorporated - general - Harold West and Rev. and Mrs. Cyril Wyche, 1928-1929. (Box 11, Folder 1)
    Folder 3 of 7.
  - Elizabeth Ann Guild, Incorporated - general - John Haynes Holmes, 1927-1928. (Box 11, Folder 2)
    Folder 4 of 7.
  - Elizabeth Ann Guild, Incorporated - general, 1927-1932. (Box 11, Folder 3)
    Folder 5 of 7.
  - Elizabeth Ann Guild, Incorporated - general, 1928. (Box 11, Folder 4)
    Folder 6 of 7.
  - Elizabeth Ann Guild, Incorporated--general, 1927-1928. (Box 11, Folder 5)
    Folder 7 of 7. With mockup of brochure for Elizabeth Ann League.
  - Elizabeth Ann Guild, Incorporated--memberships, 1927-1928. (Box 11, Folder 6)
    Folder 1 of 3.
  - Elizabeth Ann Guild, Incorporated--memberships, 1928-1929. (Box 11, Folder 7)
    Folder 2 of 3.
  - Elizabeth Ann Guild, Incorporated--memberships, 1928-1932. (Box 11, Folder 8)
    Folder 3 of 3.
  - Elizabeth Ann Guild, Incorporated--requests for illegitimacy statistics, 1927-1928.; 3 folders. (Box 11, Folder 9-10, Box 12)
  - Elizabeth Ann Guild, Incorporated--letters from friends, 1927-1929. (Box 12, Folder 2-3)
    Folders 1 and 2 of 4.
  - Elizabeth Ann Guild, Incorporated--letters from friends, 1928-1931. (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Elizabeth Ann Guild, Incorporated--letters from friends, 1931. (Box 12, Folder 5)
    Folder 4 of 4.
  - Letters from readers of The President's Daughter answered by Nan Britton, her sister or current secretary, 1927-1931. (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Letters from readers of The President's Daughter answered by Nan Britton, her sister or current secretary, 1928-1931. (Box 13, Folder 1, 3-5)
    Folders 2, 4 and 5 of 5.
  - Letters from readers of The President's Daughter answered by Nan Britton, her sister or current secretary, 1926-1931. (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Letters from readers of The President's Daughter regarding the League's work, 1928-1931. (Box 13, Folder 5-8, Box 14)
    6 folders.
  - Richard Wightman, 1926-1928. (Box 14, Folder 3)
    Folder 1 of 3. See Honesty or Politics, ch. 6, 7, 9, 11, 15.
  - Richard Wightman, 1926-1928. (Box 14, Folder 4-5)
    Folder 2 and 3 of 3.
  - Nicholas Paul Perry, C. Michael Morssen, Matrujillo, Mr. Winston, Paramount Pictures and others, 1931-1933, 1947, 1951. (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Louis Postif, Clifton Fadiman, Curtis Brown, Limited, A. & C. Boni, Incorporated and others, 1930-1935. (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Requests for interviews with Nan Britton following the publicity re the Phillips letters., 1964-1965. (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Randolph C. Downes, University of Toledo, 1960-1965. (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Dean Albertson, Brooklyn College, 1936-1964. (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - W.F. Shelton, Francis Russell, Warren Boroson (Fact Magazine), 1963-1964. (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Edwin K. Gross, 1964-1965. (Box 15, Folder 2)
- Documentary Files
  - Letter from Warren G. Harding to Nan Britton, [1917] May 9. (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Written on U.S. Senate stationery (with envelope). 3pp.
  - Letter from Warren G. Harding to Nan Britton, May 15, 1917. (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Written on Senate Chamber stationery, 4pp. (2 leaves).
  - Letter from Warren G. Harding to Nan Britton, August 11, 1917. (Box 1, Folder 3)
    Written on U.S. Senate stationery, 1 leaf.
  - Letter from Warren G. Harding to Nan Britton, May 25, 1918. (Box 1, Folder 4)
    Written on U.S. Senate, Committee on Commerce stationery, 2pp. with franked envelope.
  - Letter from Warren G. Harding to Nan Britton, December 5, 1918. (Box 1, Folder 5)
    Written on U.S. Senate, Committee on Commerce stationery, 1-1/2 pages, no envelope.
  - Letter from Warren G. Harding to Dr. Frank T. Spaulding, Superintendent of Public Schools, Cleveland, Ohio, May 25, 1918. (Box 1, Folder 6)
    Regarding my mother's changing her position as teacher. Letter of May 25, 1918 (above) sent to me same date.
  - Carbon copy of letter from Nan Britton to Warren G. Harding, May 7, 1917. (Box 1, Folder 7)
    Sent to him at Washington, D.C., to which he replied under date of May 9. Attached ia copy of carbon re-typed for clarity.
  - Carbon copy of letter from Nan Britton to Warren G. Harding, May 11, 1917. (Box 1, Folder 8)
    ... in reply to his letter of me of May 9; also re-typed for clarity.
  - Letter to Nan Britton from her mother, November 1, 1926. (Box 1, Folder 9)
    ... regarding the latter's misplacement of a letter written by Senator Harding to Mark Thompson, who was also with the Cleveland Public Schools as President of the Board of Education.... With envelope.
  - Letter from Abigail V. Harding to S.A. Willits and Miss Nan Britton, February 2, 1920. (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Letter from Abigail V. Harding to Elizabeth and Nan Britton, (probably)., June 1, 1920 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Letter from Abigail V. Harding to Nan Britton, July 24, 1920. (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Letter from Abigail V. Harding to Nan Britton, October 6, 1920. (Box 1, Folder 13)
    With envelope.
  - Letter from Abigail V. Harding to Nan Britton, October 15, 1921. (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Letter from Abigail V. Harding to Nan Britton, January 30, 1922. (Box 1, Folder 15)
    Dated per envelope.
  - Letter from Abigail V. Harding to Nan Britton, July 1, 1922. (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Letter from Abigail V. Harding to Nan Britton, July 26, 1922. (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Letter from Abigail V. Harding to Elizabeth and Nan Britton, October 7, 1922. (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Letter from Abigail V. Harding to Nan Britton, May 14, 1923. (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Letter from Abigail V. Harding to Mrs. Magnus Ericksen (Nan Britton), February 2, 1924. (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Letter from Abigail V. Harding to Mrs. Magnus Ericksen (Nan Britton), May 27, 1924. (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Letter from Abigail V. Harding to Mrs. Magnus Ericksen (Nan Britton), December 24, 1924. (Box 1, Folder 22)
    ... written Christmas Eve, 1924, after her marriage to Ralph T. Lewis, from the Princess Hotel in Bermuda where they were honeymooning - I did not keep the envelope.
  - Letter from Ralph T. Lewis to Mrs. Magnus Ericksen (Nan Britton), December 26, 1924. (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Letter from Abigail V. Harding to Nan Britton, n.d. (Saturday the 7th). (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Abigail V. Harding to Nan Britton Ericksen, May 18, 1925. (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Letter from Abigail V. Harding to Nan Britton Ericksen, May 25, 1925. (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Letter from Abigail V. Harding to Nan Britton Ericksen, September 8, 1925. (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Letter from Nan Britton to Abigail V. Harding (carbon copy), September 23, 1925. (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Letter from Nan Britton to Abigail V. Harding (carbon copy), October 5, 1925. (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Letter Nan Britton to Mrs. Carolyn H. Votaw (carbon copy), September 23, 1925. (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Letter from Mrs. Carolyn H. Votaw to Mrs. Nan B. Ericksen, September 25, 1925. (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Telegram from Mrs. A.A. Stuart (assumed name of Abigail v. Harding) to Nan B. Ericksen, October 7, 1925. (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Letter from Nan Britton to Abigail V. Harding (carbon copy), October 8, 1925. (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Letter from Abigail V. Harding to Nan B. Ericksen, October 13 (?), 1925. (Box 1, Folder 34)
    Mr. Wightman wrote on the envelope 'main admissions - important and I wrote 'Talks of effect my letter had on Mr. & Mrs. Votaw.'
  - Letter from Nan Britton to Abigail V. Harding (carbon copy), October 16, 1925. (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Letter from Nan Britton to Abigail V. Harding (carbon copy), November 12, 1925. (Box 1, Folder 36)
    Mr. Votaw had returned to me my 'Action to Annual a Marriage' which I had sent him to view, but he sent it back without any comment or note.
  - Letter from Nan Britton to Mr. And Mrs. Votaw (carbon copy) with return receipt attached, October 18, 1925. (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Letter from Nan Britton to Abigail V. Harding, October 19, 1925. (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Letter from Nan Britton to Abigail V. Harding (carbon copy), October 22, 1925. (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Letter from Abigail V. Harding to Nan B. Ericksen, October 20, 1925. (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Letter from Nan Britton to Abigail V. Harding (carbon copy), November 2, 1925. (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Letter from Abigail V. Harding to Nan B. Ericksen, November 5, 1925. (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Letter from Abigail V. Harding to Nan B. Ericksen, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Letter to Abigail V. Harding from Nan Britton (carbon copy) with bills for purchases for Elizabeth Ann attached, November 1, 1925. (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Letter from Abigail V. Harding to Nan B. Ericksen, December 9, 1925. (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Letter from Nan Britton to Abigail V. Harding (carbon copy), December 11, 1925. (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Letter from Nan Britton to Heber Herbert Votaw (carbon copy), January 27, 1926. (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - Letter from H.H. Votaw to Nan Britton, January 29, 1926. (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - Letter to H.H. Votaw from Nan Britton (carbon copy), January 28, 1926. (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - Letter from Nan Britton to H.H. Votaw (carbon copy) with registration receipt, January 30, 1926. (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - Letter from Abigail V.Harding (Lewis) to Nan B. Ericksen, February 10, 1926. (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - Telegram from Abigail V. Harding to Nan B. Ericksen, February 5, 1926. (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - Telegram from Abigail V. Harding to Nan B. Britton, February 6, 1926. (Box 1, Folder 53)
  - Letter from Nan Britton to Abigail V. Harding (carbon copy), February 1926. (Box 1, Folder 54)
    Saturday, 10:00 p.m.
  - Letter from Nan Britton to Mr. And Mrs. Votaw (carbon copy), February 1926. (Box 1, Folder 55)
    Saturday evening.
  - Text of telegram from Nan Britton to Abigail V. Harding (carbon copy), February 5, 1926. (Box 1, Folder 56)
  - Letter from Nan Britton to Abigail V. Harding (carbon copy) with registration receipt attached, February 5, 1926. (Box 1, Folder 57)
  - Letter from Nan Britton to Abigail V. Harding (carbon copy), February 12, 1926. (Box 1, Folder 58)
  - Letter from Abigail V. Harding to Nan Britton, February 24, 1926. (Box 1, Folder 59)
  - Letter from Nan Britton to Abigail V. Harding (carbon copy), March 7, 1926. (Box 1, Folder 60)
  - Letter from Nan Britton to Abigail V. Harding (carbon copy), March 14, 1926. (Box 1, Folder 61)
  - Letter from Abigail V. Harding to Nan B. Ericksen, March 20, 1926. (Box 1, Folder 62)
  - Letter from Nan Britton to Abigail V. Harding, March 24, 1926. (Box 1, Folder 63)
  - Letter from Abigail V. Harding to Nan B. Ericksen, March 25, 1926. (Box 1, Folder 64)
  - Letter from Nan Britton to Abigail V. Harding (carbon copy), April 4, 1926. (Box 1, Folder 65)
  - Letter from Nan Britton to Dr. Harding, brother of Warren Harding (carbon copy), April 4, 1926. (Box 1, Folder 66)
  - Letter from Nan Britton to Abigail V. Harding (carbon copy), April 30, 1926. (Box 1, Folder 67)
  - Facsimile of bank draft from Abigail V. Harding to Nan Britton for $40.00, July 2, 1926. (Box 1, Folder 68)
    Marion County Bank Company, no.A16827. With envelope.
  - Letter from Nan Britton to Abigail V. Harding (carbon copy), July 7, 1926. (Box 1, Folder 69)
  - Letter from Abigail v. Harding enclosing money order, with facsimile of the money order, June 4, 1926. (Box 1, Folder 70)
    Written from Troy, Ohio, but postmarked Hillsboro.
  - Letter from Nan Britton to Abigail V. Harding (carbon copy), June 17, 1926. (Box 1, Folder 71)
  - Letter from Abigail V. Harding to Nan Britton, July 16, 1926. (Box 1, Folder 72)
  - Letter from Nan Britton to Abigail V. Harding (carbon copy), July 22, 1926. (Box 1, Folder 73)
  - Letter from Abigail V. Harding to Nan Britton, August 7, 1926. (Box 1, Folder 74)
    Dated per envelope. With Nan Britton's note, This was the last letter received from Miss H.
  - Christmas card from Abigail V. Harding to Nan Britton, unsigned, December 21, 1926. (Box 1, Folder 75)
    With envelope. Nan Britton's note: containing a cashier's check for $25.00.
  - Letter from Abigail V. Harding to Nan Britton's sister, Elizabeth, (?)., 1924 (Box 1, Folder 76)
  - Calling card for Abigail Victoria Harding, 1911. (Box 1, Folder 77)
    Nan Britton's note: ... accompanied a little gift to me back in my high school days ...
  - Calling card for Heber Herbert Votaw, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 78)
  - Calling card for Harry W. Perrin, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 79)
  - Letter from Nan Britton to Jim Sloan (carbon copy) with return receipt, February 5, 1926. (Box 1, Folder 80)
    Return receipt dated February 5, 1926.
  - Text of telegram from Nan Britton to Jim Sloan (carbon copy), February 1926. (Box 1, Folder 81)
  - Letter from Jim Sloan to Nan Britton, March 19, 1926. (Box 1, Folder 82)
  - Letter from Nan Britton to Jim Sloan (carbon copy), March 20, 1926. (Box 1, Folder 83)
  - Letter from Nan Britton to Jim Sloan (carbon copy), March 24, 1926. (Box 1, Folder 84)
  - Note from Jim Sloan to Nan Britton, May 18, 1926. (Box 1, Folder 85)
  - Letter from Nan Britton to Harding Memorial Association (carbon copy), May 19, 1926. (Box 1, Folder 86)
  - Letter from Nan Britton to Jim Sloan (carbon copy), May 20, 1926. (Box 1, Folder 87)
  - Letter from Nan Britton to Jim Sloan (carbon copy), May 25, 1926. (Box 1, Folder 88)
    With program from laying of the cornerstone for the Harding Memorial.
  - Letter from Jim Sloan to Nan Britton, November 8, 1926. (Box 1, Folder 89)
  - Letter from Jim Sloan to Nan Britton, January 18, 1927. (Box 1, Folder 90)
    Sent to Nan Britton in care of a friend.
  - Letter from Pris to Nan Britton, March 16, 1927. (Box 1, Folder 91)
  - Letter from Nan Britton to Gen. Charles E. Dawes (carbon copy), May 15, 1926. (Box 1, Folder 92)
    Nan Britton's note: See The President's Daughter, episode no.166, p.379 re this.
  - Photograph of Warren G. Harding inscribed To Miss Nan Britton ... Sincerely, Warren G. Harding., n.d. (Box 1, Folder 93)
  - Photograph of Miss Abigail Victoria Harding (later Mrs. Ralph T. Lewis) inscribed: Most sincerely yours, Abigail Victoria Harding., n.d. (Box 1, Folder 94)
  - Photograph of Carolyn Harding (Mrs. Heber Herbert Votaw, inscribed: Yours truly, Carolyn Votaw., n.d. (Box 1, Folder 95)
  - Photograph of Dr. George Tryon Harding, father fo Warren G. Harding, Victoria and Carolyn Harding, inscribed: Yours truly, G.T. Harding. (Box 1, Folder 96)
  - Photograph of Lila Wesener, inscribed: To Miss Nan Britton -- / With and all good wishes from / her admiring friend, ' Lila Wesener. (Box 1, Folder 97)
    Nan Britton's note The latter inscription was cut from the photograph because I wanted to frame the latter 'close-up' but I kept the inscription. Lila Wesener was a cousin of the Harding sisters and brothers.
  - Wallet of Warren G. Harding, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 98)
    Nan Britton's note: ... (his name imprinted in gold), given to me by Carrie Votaw when I was a guest in their home in Tacoma Park, Washington, D.C. (see p.308, The President's Daughter).
  - Notarized statement of Mrs. Mary Lee Britton (Nan Britton's mother) regarding a visit of Elizabeth Britton Willits (Nan Brittons sister) to Mr. Harding at Marion, Ohio, after the election, August 4, 1928. (Box 1, Folder 99)
    15pp. Holograph.
  - Statement from Nan Britton's sister, Elizabeth Britton Willits, regarding her knowledge of Nan Britton's receipt of letters from Mr. Harding, January 4, 1960. (Box 1, Folder 100)
    Notarized.
  - Letter from Mrs. Jack (Mary) Pusey regarding her suspicions of Mr. Harding's paternity and Nan Britton's reply (carbon copy), December 31, 1931 and January 2, 1932. (Box 1, Folder 101)
    Dated per envelope. Mrs. Pusey called Mrs. P.J. Johnson in The President's Daughter. Nan Britton's note: I resided in the home (apartment) of the Puseys for two years during which time I was seeing Mr. Harding.
  - Snapshot of Warren G. Harding which Nan Britton loved and carried for years. (Box 1, Folder 102)
    Nan Britton's additional note: This one is in The President's Daughter, opposite p.60. (Snapshot sent to me by Warren G. Harding).
  - Another Snapshot of Warren G. Harding which Nan Britton loved and carried almost as long as the one above. (Box 1, Folder 103)
    Nan Britton's note: (This one acquired I don't recall how. It appears to have been taken at the White House).
  - Snapshot of Nan Britton, Harding booster in the pre-election days of, 1920. 1920. (Box 1, Folder 104)
    Taken on Labor Day.
  - Photograph of Mr. Harding taken at Edmonston Studio, Washington, D.C (Box 2, Folder 1)
    Nan Britton's note: This was the first photograph Mr. Harding sent me - when I lived at 412 E. 58th St., New York City, with my father's college classmate's family (Mr. & Mrs. Grove D. Curtis and daughter Anna), in the spring of 1917.
  - Newspaper picture of Abigail and Carolyn, 1920. (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Photograph of Warren G. Harding by Pach, 1920. (Box 2, Folder 3)
    Nan Britton's note: ... displayed in the Pach Fifth Avenue window in August of 1923. Returning from France on learning of Mr. Harding's death, I chanced to see it and bought this copy.
  - Letter from the Ithaca Conservatory of Music to Scott Willits (Nan Britton's brother-in-law), part of letter from Elizabeth Willits and Nan Britton's note re this letter, December 18, 1920. (Box 2, Folder 4)
    Nan Britton's note: I took this letter with me when I met Mr. Harding at the Statler Hotel in Cleveland ..., see p.143 - Ep. 58, The President's Daughter.
  - Letter from Governor James M. Cox of Ohio to Nan Britton, June 28, 1918. (Box 2, Folder 5)
    Nan Brittons note: ... offering to assist my brother find a suitable position. My brother never used the letter ... see p.161, episode 64 in The President's Daughter.
  - Glossy print of a photograph of President Harding and full-length snapshot of Elizabeth Ann Harding - The Likeness. (Box 2, Folder 6)
    See p.197, The President's Daughter.
  - Photo of Elizabeth Ann with her Harding book., June 1921. (Box 2, Folder 7)
    Nan Britton's note: ... taken in back yard of my sister E's apartment on La Fayette Parkway, Chgo ...
  - Photo of Nan Britton holding Elizabeth Ann, September 1920. (Box 2, Folder 8)
    Nan Britton's note: Taken in front of apt. house where lived the nurse who took care of E.A. for over a year.
  - Pressed flower from President Harding's desk in the White House, June 1921. (Box 2, Folder 9)
    Nan Britton's note: See episode 62, p.156 [The President's Daughter].
  - Page from The Marion Daily Star containing a photograph of Nan Britton at age 5, February 1, 1902. (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Remaining empty pages of diary kept by Nan Britton, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 11)
    Nan Britton's note: ... the written pages torn out and destroyed at the request of Mr. Harding to my sister Elizabeth who confided to him that I was keeping the diary.
  - Facsimile of registration of G.H. Harvey & wife, Cleveland, at the Imperial Hotel, New York (Box 2, Folder 12)